<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AVT on KAY SINGH</title><link>https://singhkays.github.io/tags/avt/</link><description>Recent content in AVT on KAY SINGH</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © 2017–2020, Kay Singh; all rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://singhkays.github.io/tags/avt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AV1 Ecosystem Update: May 2019</title><link>https://singhkays.github.io/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-may-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://singhkays.github.io/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-may-2019/</guid><description>May was another amazing month for the AV1 codec! We saw great progress in the SVT-AV1 encoder, Android update news and some surprising news out of China!
SVT-AV1 is making strides! Let&amp;rsquo;s start with SVT-AV1 encoder, the current encoder of choice for Netflix, being developed by the folks at Intel. In May, version 0.5.0 was released with the following features:
8 bit / 10 bit 4:2:0 up to 4K60p resolutions Presets 0-8 New API, FFmpeg, GStreamer plugins Rate control support (VBR, CVBR) Block sizes from 4x4 to 128x128 Non-square blocks Tiles Deblocking / CDEF / Restoration filters Film Grain Warped motion estimation Intra block copy Trellis quantized coefficient optimization Support for 4 and 5 layers prediction structures Chroma search in MD Multi-reference picture support Other notable updates May also saw the most number of commits to the SVT-AV1 Github repo as shown by the graph below.</description></item><item><title>AV1 Ecosystem Update: April 2019</title><link>https://singhkays.github.io/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-april-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://singhkays.github.io/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-april-2019/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been an exciting time following the progress of the royalty free video codec AV1 over the past year and April might just be the most exciting active month in the amount of news we got about AV1! It&amp;rsquo;s not every day that media industry giants such as Netflix, Google, Mozilla, Microsoft, Apple, Amazon, ARM, Facebook, Nvidia, Intel, Cisco and many others agree on the same technology stack!
Samsung joins the party The month started with Samsung announcing they were joining the Alliance of Open Media Board at the highest level.</description></item></channel></rss>