<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Video Compression on KAY SINGH</title>
    <link>https://singhkays.com/tags/video-compression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video Compression on KAY SINGH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017–2021, Kay Singh; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://singhkays.com/tags/video-compression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AV1 2019: A Year In Review</title>
      <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-2019-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-2019-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s not often you see so many logos of tech giants on one page backing the same technology. In my experience, every enterprise has developed a case of NIH and come up with their standards. No surprise then that there&amp;rsquo;s an XKCD describing this phenomenon!
But when the AV1 1.0.0 spec was finalized in 2018, with the backing of so many giants, the world knew AV1 would be a serious piece of tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s time to replace GIFs with AV1 video!</title>
      <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/its-time-replace-gifs-with-av1-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://singhkays.com/blog/its-time-replace-gifs-with-av1-video/</guid>
      <description>It is 2019 and we need to make a decision about GIFs (no, not that one! We’re never going to be able to decide that one!). GIFs take up a massive amount of space (often multiple megabytes!) and if you’re a web developer, then that’s completely against your ethos! As a web developer, you want to minimize the bits your users need to download so that your website loads fast. That’s why you minify javascript, optimize PNGs, JPEGs and sometimes turn JPEGs to WebPs as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing x265 encoder scaling on a 128 core Azure VM for 4K HDR</title>
      <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/x265-128-core-scaling-4k-hevc-hdr-azure-vm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 13:52:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://singhkays.com/blog/x265-128-core-scaling-4k-hevc-hdr-azure-vm/</guid>
      <description>Video encoding has always been a fairly compute intensive task. With every new generation of video encoders, more computational power has been required to achieve the compression benefits. HEVC/H.265 is the latest state of the art video compression standard with x265 being the most popular open-source encoder used for encoding into the HEVC/H.265 format. In comparison to AVC/H.264 (the previous state of the art encoding format), HEVC offers about double the data compression ratio at the same level of video quality, or substantially improved video quality at the same bit rate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
