<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vimeo on KAY SINGH</title>
    <link>https://singhkays.com/tags/vimeo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vimeo on KAY SINGH</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017–2020, Kay Singh; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://singhkays.com/tags/vimeo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AV1 2019: A Year In Review</title>
      <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-2019-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-2019-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s not often you see so many logos of tech giants on one page backing the same technology. In my experience, every enterprise has developed a case of NIH and come up with their standards. No surprise then that there&amp;rsquo;s an XKCD describing this phenomenon!
But when the AV1 1.0.0 spec was finalized in 2018, with the backing of so many giants, the world knew AV1 would be a serious piece of tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AV1 Ecosystem Update: August 2019</title>
      <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-august-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-august-2019/</guid>
      <description>AVIF in Spectrum lib While browsing for AV1/AVIF updates, I noticed this commit to Facebook&amp;rsquo;s open source Spectrum library that adds support for AVIF format.
 https://github.com/facebookincubator/spectrum/commit/89b87bee831d3c7aabd0ad327fb118ce699df55d  Spectrum is an image transcoding library for iOS and Android that is meant to be integrated into apps for image operations. Hopefully this means that we&amp;rsquo;ll see apps supporting AVIF format soon!
FFmpeg 4.2 release FFmpeg 4.2 codenamed &amp;ldquo;Ada&amp;rdquo; was released on August 5th, 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AV1 Ecosystem Update: July 2019</title>
      <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-july-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-july-2019/</guid>
      <description>If May and June were F1 race cars in terms of speed of AV1 development, then July would probably be a Honda Civic. After numerous exciting announcements in the previous month, July felt like everyone&amp;rsquo;s on vacation, which is probably true because summer months tend to be slow as the school&amp;rsquo;s out. So, this update will be a short one as I&amp;rsquo;m out on vacation as well :)
Mile High Video 2019 Nathan Egge of Mozilla and Brion Vibber of Wikimedia presented a session recapping AV1&amp;rsquo;s progress in the last year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AV1 Ecosystem Update: June 2019</title>
      <link>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-june-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://singhkays.com/blog/av1-ecosystem-update-june-2019/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a pretty busy for me professionally which is why this month&amp;rsquo;s AV1 ecosystem update is coming in pretty late. It&amp;rsquo;s been one of the most exciting months for AV1 development and a lot to catch up on! With so much news this month, it is starting to feel like we&amp;rsquo;re at the cusp of something big! (which we hope AV1 will be )
Youtube pauses AV1 rollout Currently, YouTube is the biggest streaming platform delivering AV1 video and is responsible for the majority of AV1 video consumption on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
